Simon Yuen-Curriculum Vitae

PERSONAL PARTICULARS

Name: Yuen Ho Ming, Simon

Telephone: 6573 9314

Email: hyman415@gmail.com

Address: Flat B, 3/F, Poksmith Villa,40, Pokfield Road, Kennedy Town, Hong Kong

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

An enthusiastic and dedicated individual with experience in fund accounting and banking industry. Attentive to details with a logical and analytical approach to solve problems and issues. Process excellent interpersonal skill, communication and negotiation skills to communicate professionally with customers. Work effectively on own initiative with the organization and complete assignments on time and to the required standard.

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

2010-2013 The University of Manchester, United Kingdom

Bachlor of Arts (Economic and Social Studies)(Hon) Accounting and Finance

2009-2010 Bellerbys College (Cambridge), United Kingdom

Business Foundation, Pass with Distinction 79%

2004-2009 St Paul's College, Hong Kong

Hong Kong Certificate Education of Examination (2009)

WORK EXPERIENCE AND JOB DUTIES

Sep 2016- Present Alter Domus, Fund Service Officer

Permanent Full time

- Complete due diligence including KYC and anti-money laundering (AML) on Funds and related parties
- Implementation of systems and processes
- Review of fund documents such as PPM/Offering Memorandum, SLA and transaction documents with various parties
- Production of financial statements and fund reporting
- Preparation of NAV statements for investors
- Maintenance of general ledger
- Supervision of audit process
- Capital call Management, including monitoring of bank accounts
- Coordinate cash management and treasury services
- Coaching inexperience staff

Oct 2013- Sep 2016 HSBC, Global Asset Management (HK) Ltd, Accountant

Contract Full time

- Process strong technical expertise in the exercise of financial control, including financial accounting, cost accounting and fee calculations.
- Demonstrate expertise in formulating and overseeing financial processing systems, procedures and control mechanisms of business.
- Ensure that financial processing system provide accurate and timely information required by line of business management
- Planning and implementing new financial processing system to enhance efficiency.
- Demonstrate sound judgement and analytical skills on monthly fee reports
- Actively involved in updating and reviewing documentations on finance manual
- Coaching internal staff at offshore centre

WORK EXPERIENCE AND JOB DUTIES (Continue)

June 2012- Aug 2012 HLM & Co. CPA, Vacation Trainee (Audit)

Internship Full time

- Provide professional audit and tax services to the following listed company: China Water Property Group Limited (HK Stock code: 02349)
- Perform special audits and reports for their restructuring project.
- Work as a team to deal with tax authority's enquiries and estimated assessment on client's corporation.

AWARDS & CERTIFICATES

- HKICPA Student Member with Conversion Programme Certificates (Audit, Tax, Law)
- International English Language Testing System(IELTS):Overall 7

FURTHER DETAILS

- IT Proficiency: Excel, Word, PowerPoint and basic VBA
- Languages: Cantonese (native), English, Mandarin & Basic Japanese

Expected Salary: Negotiable